Justin Cano

https://jstncno.dev Santa Clara, CA | jstncno@gmail.com | 650.255.0098

ABOUT

I am currently working as a **Tech Lead** on the **Experience Studio team** at **Google**.

The Experience Studio team leads the design and production of physical spaces that tell Google's story, make Google's magic more apparent, and communicate Google's ability to grow customers' businesses into the digital age and guide their brands into the future.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, RIVERSIDE

BS IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING June 2014 | Riverside, CA

LINKS

https://jstncno.dev Github://jstncno LinkedIn://justincano

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Proficient in:

TypeScript • Python • HTML/CSS JavaScript

With some experience in:

Scala • Bash • C/C++ • Java • SQL

FRAMEWORKS AND TOOLS

Angular • React • Unity Hadoop • Spark • Airflow

PLATFORMS

macOS • Linux • Windows Raspberry Pi • Arduino GCP • AWS

INTERESTS

Intersection of the physical and digital Software design and development Embedded devices • AR • AI Finance • Energy • Robotics User Experience • Creative coding + various other trends in tech

WORK EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE | Technical Lead. Experience Studio

Jun 2019 - Present | Mountain View, CA

- Advocate technology decisions for software deployed in our global portfolio of Experience Centers
- Contribute to the design and implementation of proprietary show control software platform to interface with AV systems (e.g. Crestron)
- Lead development of Python and TypeScript client libraries and distribute to external exhibit developers
- Lead development of an Electron app using service account authentication for kiosk exhibits
- Created a custom Debian OS USB installer with preloaded scripts used for running exhibit software
- Collaborate with cross-disciplinary teams to design, develop, and deploy interactive technology exhibits
- Provide technical leadership, direction, and guidance for a team of engineers

K2 PARTNERING SOLUTIONS @ GOOGLE | EXPERIENCE ENGINEER

Sep 2017 - Jun 2019 | Mountain View, CA

• Developed software applications for physical spaces that personify Google in the real world, playfully showcasing Google technology to inspire wonder and delight to Google's top clients

RALLY HEALTH | SOFTWARE DATA ENGINEER

Sep 2015 - Sep 2017 | San Francisco, CA

- Maintained on-call SRE on analytics pipeline for nightly data aggregation jobs
- Contributed to the development of client libraries for collecting analytics
- Developed software release automation and CI/CD processes using Jenkins

INSIGHT DATA SCIENCE | Data Engineering Fellow

Jun 2015 - Jul 2015 | Palo Alto, CA

- Participated in a Data Engineering Fellowship to learn how to use and implement Big Data tools in the Hadoop ecosystem
- Built a data pipeline that extracts and builds a hyperlink graph from Common Crawl's April 2015 web corpus using HDFS, Spark, GraphX, and HBase

LOQATE | SUPPORT ENGINEER

Nov 2014 - May 2015 | San Mateo, CA

• Software Engineer on the Support Team, providing software support to clients

JETHEAD DEVELOPMENT | SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Jun 2013 - Sep 2013 | Carlsbad, CA

 Software Engineer Intern, providing bug fixes and enhancements for DirecTV Set-Top-Boxes

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

RASPBERRY PI CAMCORDER - UCR ENTOMOLOGY

Jun 2014 – Jul 2014 | Riverside, CA

https://jstncno.dev/dl/Kistner-et-al.pdf

Spent a summer developing a Raspberry Pi camcorder for the University of California, Riverside Entomology Department to capture footage of insect eggs to aid in their research

Technologies used: Raspberry Pi, Python